<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Software Ramblings</title><id>https://iwillig.github.io/feeds/tags/design.xml</id><subtitle>Tag: design</subtitle><updated>2024-12-28T22:14:07Z</updated><link href="https://iwillig.github.io/feeds/tags/design.xml" rel="self" /><link href="https://iwillig.github.io" /><entry><title>Hello, World</title><id>https://iwillig.github.io/hello-world.html</id><author><name>Ivan Willig</name><email>iwillig@gmail.com</email></author><updated>2024-12-28T12:00:00Z</updated><link href="https://iwillig.github.io/hello-world.html" rel="alternate" /><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Welcome&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Software Ramblings, my new technical blog. I am a
professional software engineer with over 16 years of experience. I
hope this blog will encourage me to write about my experiences,
learnings and observations about software engineering. I am also
making this blog public and hopefully other people will find some of
this useful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This blog is going to cover software design, functional programming,
API design and more. It will focus on the Clojure programming
language, but should include other languages like JavaScript,
TypeScript, Rust, Scheme and SQL.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have several goals for 2025, and I will be using this blog to record
my efforts in reaching these goals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2025 Goals&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope to learn or better understand the following software systems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn about Game Development&lt;/strong&gt;: Since I was a kid and playing Red Alert at my
friend John's house I have wanted to build a Command and Conquer or
StarCraft like game. I want to make 2025 the year when I finally
understand game development and build something.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn more about Immutable Linux&lt;/strong&gt;: Understand and better use immutable Linux
distros. NixOS, Gnu Guix, Fedora Sliverblue are all modern
&amp;quot;immutable&amp;quot; distributions.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deepen my understanding of Pandoc&lt;/strong&gt;: Pandoc is an advance
document transformation system. It allows you to convert any
document into any other document. It also includes a
&amp;quot;transformation&amp;quot; system that allow you to modify documents.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deepen my understanding Rest API and GraphQL API&lt;/strong&gt;: Continue to
learn and write about the best ways to design and build these type
of API Systems.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</content></entry></feed>